there's only three days remaining on my
merch campaign take a look at the link
in the description if you want a pesky
bird t-shirt or a grain let's get into
the episode we're starting today's
episode in the mycelium resistance
headquarters mother spore in the big boy
chair
now here's the thing
take a good look at this room
because over there
mr doc
is doing some crazy stuff
and if you listen carefully
there's some pretty there's some pretty
spooky noises
and i think
that the interior here is significantly
improved thanks to xb
and i'm actually genuinely terrified of
being in here i don't know what the
triggers are but doc assures me that
it's ready to be primed now that i think
that's what he's doing he's getting it
ready to be absolutely secure
and we're about to find out
how well that goes so this is this is
why i'm saying it's about the principle
everything is ready to go and it is
dangerous so let's back away slowly and
not touch
absolutely anything even though there's
a button that i really want to press i
hope whatever doc's making doesn't
destroy my beautiful mushroom castle
because it really is beautiful mushroom
castle i actually forgot about the llama
it looks so good
okay we're heading over to the base
where i've already done
a whole bunch of work
so while we're flying take a look at
this very very quick time lapse of me
finishing gritting my teeth and
finishing off what is going on with my
portal situation
seriously
one two three this is a mess anyway
check this out six hours this took by
the way six painful hours yeah this
footage is like sped up over a thousand
times as you can see each little flash
is day and night
and ta-da
we have ourselves a big
big
hole
and i left myself the diamond door
because there's some i can't do it i
can't i can't waste diamond ore on a
time lapse no no no no no the little
tingle has to be enjoyed as if i didn't
need more diamonds but for you know
excavating this huge area this isn't
actually a lot of diamonds this is a
very inefficient way of doing it all
right a stuck in a bit of diamonds isn't
too bad but you may have also noticed
there's a giant
square box right here
now while i was making this i was
fighting slimes non-stop
and so i figured out that there is two
slime chunks down here and this
is the area
that they spawn in
which is very good news for me because
this means
there's a very natural reason to make a
farm here i can make a pretty cool slime
farm and because it's so close to the
mansion i can integrate it into the
design and make this place
more functional so it's def it's like
this was meant to be
so you can see i've marked out the area
and i'm going to consider how on earth
i'm going to design the mansion to kind
of
go over this and have an entrance of its
own and what i'm gonna do with this
giant hole now that i've actually
finished mining it out there was also
another huge benefit to mining all of
this out and that is shulker boxes and
shulker boxes full of materials which of
course
we are going to put in the barge on the
second floor which is going to be barge
box central just
like
this check it out we got piles and piles
of shulker boxes full of stuff i love
how i cut to that pretending like no
time has passed at all it's been a full
day it took me an entire day
to get boxes of rockets
uh even just inventory management so we
got we got ourselves some cobblestone we
got ourselves some stone we got
ourselves some diorite i don't know if
these are even gonna sell i imagine
these will
but i i am pretty pleased with how this
has come out it's just it's very
lifeless and soulless in here at the
moment so there's a there's a definite
series of tidying up that needs to
happen
and i also have to figure out how i'm
gonna make people pay for this like
these are kind of clunky right here so
cobblestone six diamonds per box
i think that's a pretty good price given
that i mean you get a shulker box and
all of that i know that see
cobblestone's one of those things that
you have in abundance but sometimes when
you need it you need a lot of it and you
don't have that much of it
now speaking of shops
awesome segway green do you guys
remember last episode when i showed you
my little boy grain it's time for a bit
of shameless self-promotion right now uh
my senior guys may be meeting
no
no you're interrupting my merch plug no
i need to i need to explain about my
match so i want to say oh he's going to
hit the emergency meeting button this
this is getting into whoa
my plug was being interrupted how can i
shamelessly promote if i'm what is going
on here
oh
my
goodness gracious me
well butter migraine
what is going on
i have been bamboozled i have been
baffled i think i think we've been
pranked oh my goodness that's lava
dripping okay okay okay hello hello does
anybody know what's going on here i have
some suspicions hello is that scar
i have some suspicions too oh my
goodness what is going on hello there
gentlemen um beat up sent me a message
and i had no idea what's going on i
don't even have my moccasins on for the
day and then i've come in here and i
find you all in jail
and look at this there's this switch and
it pours lava
knife
[Music]
[Laughter]
can we not just leave
no no no no no no
you guys are all in prison now for great
crimes against hermitcraft spreading
spores you couldn't look like more of
the bad guy right now you got a monocle
and you you've put us in jail
it's solid gold
no i'm the good guy i mean we we we may
look sometimes like the bad guy i mean
we have death lasers and stuff but it's
all for the greater good that's what
every bad guy thinks that's literally
what every bad guy thinks i mean that
looks like a juicy target over there i
think i might just take this the thing
is i could just go like this because i
mean how did you and then i could also
do this no no no no
no no no more lava no more lava can you
actually
did you do what i think you did have you
hijacked our emergency meeting
oh oh yeah yeah bw btw set this all up
and uh basically i've called you all
here for a meeting i will just lower the
lava on you guys and uh
i've got stuff on me i've got stuff on
me
time out time out timeout white flag
white flag white i am my hands are off
the levers off the levers let's let's
talk this out you know negotiation style
oh uh a parlay a pi hello oh hello b
double o oh there there he is
look at that man all right that's
you know scott we should maybe time out
take this
take this somewhere else and we'll we'll
chat about this negotiate parlay
should we meet up in the llama
the giant llama
yes the crimes against hep the llama
okay we'll meet up in the llama all
right okay hold on i'll just kill you
guys out of there hold on i'm just gonna
i think you've been
keeping it out no no no no no uh there's
a raid going on
what around here
oh that's not good is it see the rainbow
oh no they're like outside boomers
no no that happened now who had bad omen
not me no that that may or may not have
been me
how are you doing that scar
doing
[Laughter]
what am i doing you're swimming are you
swimming away
i am what you're yeah you're swimming on
the road
no i'm i'm standing
walk backwards
please oh
man this mare is not clamping down on
crime
no it's true
hey out of my chair
hey that's my chair this is
i think
i think we can both agree that this
turf war has gone on too long and i
don't actually see
the end i disagree oh yeah you just got
here okay
we want peace here but i do feel like
we need to decide who wins and who loses
well um we have the laser beam and that
means we're automatically winners that
that's not what i meant
somebody back me up last season we did a
giant civil war we did like a big pvp
capture the flag thing and
i don't want to do that again i want to
do something slightly differently so i
have actually oh thank you oh
i was getting excited i was well i was
thinking we said all this like real
human beings
through sports what if we
made some mini games like each team made
mini games i've been thinking about this
it's been brewing for a while you see we
each make mini games and then we have a
few rules surrounding it that we can
work out later but the the winner of the
most mini games who gets the most points
wins the war bingo bango and
we'll probably like i don't know what
the consequences here consequences the
loser has to restore the island
we gotta sweeten that but we don't have
to think about it quite yet there's
gotta be more to it it's gonna be more
into that winning
firm good nice
thank you i i'm doing good over here
look at me you're doing great
is is it like sports in real life like
what kind of mini games so i guess
that's up to each team and how many
people want to do it we've got we've got
some logistics to work out but if you
agree to it we can have a mini game
showdown to decide who the winner of
this war is i agree to it and i think
that is a good idea i think that'll be a
fun thing we can do we can all build our
games and then uh we can all
congratulate hep when we win
if you lose scott i want you to help me
build my base
[Music]
all the mycelium resistance members just
looked at each other
[Laughter]
wait what is this what the ride's been
all about green
you're based on the back of your mansion
no i don't want to say that was a master
plan but scott if you lose seriously the
back of the mansion it really needs some
attention all right so many games it is
then i guess all right let's get out of
our tower but nobody said the minigames
can't be lethal right oh no no no no
yeah yeah go nuts that was the strangest
interaction and i actually have
forgotten that i was in the middle
of talking to you guys about my merch
but first i need to address something
okay so that little wager with scar was
a spur of the moment thing um i
definitely cut out my team there i
i just saw the opportunity like if they
lose
scar has to help me build the back of
the mansion it's perfect and let's just
pretend that that was the plan the whole
time this whole war was about getting
scar
to build the back of my mansion we'll
probably add to the wager it'd be funny
if everyone had a different wager with
different people but we'll see what the
outcome of this is so we've got an idea
and everyone agreed to it
we just need to work out the logistics
of it so
i'll come up with something but first
can i go back to um oh man i lost my
grain i ate grain hold on this just
won't do ah
there you are okay so
now that that is firmly out of the way
what i wanted to say to you guys earlier
was a massive and i mean
massive thank you the amount of people
that have shown support for the channel
by buying this little guy here i've got
to admit this little guy here he was the
most popular t-shirt but it was very
close between this one and pesky bird i
am absolutely gobsmacked and i need to
remind you all that
you only have a few days remaining to
purchase a t-shirt if you want the
shipping in time for the holiday season
so
just a friendly reminder and another
shameless self-promotion on the channel
if you want one of these one of these
cute little guys or if you want my
personal favorite the pesky bird i've
been wearing mine all day and i really
love it if you want one of those check
the link in the description to my merch
store end of self promotion let's crack
on with the rest of the episode because
i think we have some logistics to work
out so what i'm gonna do is make a
little proposal for scar
and then see if he agrees we need to
figure out a way of making this whole
thing
work for everyone
and i already have a couple of ideas for
minigames i have taken the time
to create turf war
end game this is all the information and
boy oh boy i know why you clicked on
today's green episode it's to read signs
in minecraft because that's what we love
doing in hermitcraft reading signs
okay but it's something we have to do
anyway this war has gone on long enough
a finale has been agreed between the hep
and the resistance each team will create
five mini games that may change to four
or three depending on what goes on it
can be 1v1 2v2 3v3 etc pvp games are
allowed but not necessary also you can
add a wager with the opposition to make
it more interesting you're encouraged to
get creative with your games
and they will begin on the 11th of
december meaning you only have seven
days to create your mini game and then
each one will get a point and if there's
a tie podzel party will make the
tiebreaker and then the loser
has to restore
the shopping district to its former
grassy glory
so that is endgame and now i just want
to take scar through this and get an
agreement in place
and he is just here oh man you know what
that means
is he afk
oh yeah he he's afk oh no he's standing
on a slab don't worry i can solve this
hello scar hello i have created as you
can see a giant dirt wall underneath the
town hall with all of the information
that i have already read to my audience
so i'm definitely not gonna read it
again they did not click this video to
have signs read to them
i i'm gonna require the signs to be read
here no okay i'm gonna you know i'm
gonna cut to black for a second you you
read those signs and then we're gonna
discuss whether you agree to it me and
my viewers don't care about signs we're
good okay basically it's the mini game
thing do you agree
to the terms and conditions that i have
written out here of how this thing will
go down
that's a lot of text i think i made a
good decision um yeah i've elected to
lead not to read i just scroll through
the terms and conditions and then accept
okay awesome so the only thing that i
really want to add here is
a wager with you that i mentioned
earlier and everyone was like green why
you cut me out well i was thinking what
if
everyone kind of waged with each other
at free will so i'm gonna i'm gonna
offer my wager with you
if the resistance win scar must help
green build
the back of his base
okay all right all right that's a good
one that that's a good one that that's
that's a sizeable amount of work that is
a lot of work and it's been put off for
about nine months now so the question is
it's very possible that hep could win so
if hep win
what do you want and don't say the barge
because you're not getting the barge all
right oh gosh oh oh oh oh oh oh i got
something i got something
okay i want my plot back
from aqua town
[Laughter]
no
yes aqua town plot but i planned that so
far ahead
that was a long time ago and it is right
in the prime spot where
skyrick's tower is gonna go so okay this
is your new project i mean it's looking
fancy by the way but uh i purchased a
very long time ago when you were
planning all this out i just right under
your nose i purchased this prime spot
and i've been waiting for you to build
here oh man
i don't want to give this up okay
there's nothing else you want um no but
i also uh just this just to sweeten the
pie you have to wear a minecraft head
of my choosing for a certain amount of
time like an episode okay deal deal
really deal
okay i'm confident we can win i'm
confident we can win there we go right
it's i like it we shake off i like it
yes um three two one
oh okay i did a spin for whatever reason
so the only other thing we need to work
out
where is this happening
um because there's nothing that there's
not a lot of space left in the shopping
district but i have already scouted
ahead
and i kind of want this to be near the
mini-game district and the only place is
this peninsula in the mesa over here now
i have already asked ren and he said
yeah go ahead
so what do you think about here there's
like a little shallow area if we work
together we could create a nice like
arena hopefully big enough for
six to eight mini games yeah no this
this is fantastic i think the best part
about it is that it's not in deep ocean
exactly
okay i can wade through the water
we've got a lot of work to do wow this
is gonna be a lot of fun actually and
there's a lot of writing on this there
is a lot of riding on this we need to
encourage everyone including the viewers
they need to encourage their favorite
hermits to make a wager of some kind
maybe there's something that people want
maybe there's something that b dubs has
that impulse really wants and
i don't know i think the more wages the
better can i make another wager with
another resistance member if you want
but i'm not going to because i
definitely don't want to end up in debt
to like four different people
if you wanna if you if you feel
confident then i mean go ahead if i win
the mansion gets done i mean i
that's that's the thing if i win
skyrim's tower is gonna look beautiful
and not like half agreed
all right i guess we gotta go work on
yeah we gotta go do games let's do this
let the others know
so we know what's going on there we are
creating lots of mini games to decide
who wins now
i need to pay a visit to the giant
spanner works
that is mumbo's base because a few days
ago it was mumbo's birthday and i was a
pretty bad friend actually and i forgot
to send him a card
but
uh to be honest with you in real life
and this is serious i don't do cards
like i don't like receiving cards and i
don't like sending cards i think they're
bad for the environment but i'm still a
bad friend i didn't get him a card so
what i'm gonna do instead what's that
noise
i think mumbo's base is
that's really creepy i don't think i
like that so to make up for it i am
going to make mumbo a little birthday
present
it may look slightly like a christmas
present but it's not
it's a birthday present
and what's going in this giant red
present for mumbo
well arguably the most dangerous and
silly thing that i can ever provide
one
freshly printed
green iou that means
mumbo will own
and i owe you something which he can
cash in at any time and of course it's
within reason he can't just say oh green
i'm going to cash in the iou give me the
barge no it doesn't work like that it's
got to be it's got to be sensible and
it's got to be agreeable so i can of
course turn it down but it's still
pretty dangerous a favor from green
is one
weird thing i probably you probably
thought i was gonna give him grain
i.e one ready boy what is this heartbeat
oh
i should have put the present close to
his heart
but i don't really want to be near it
because it's weird
so here we go one one iou from green
happy
birthday
sorry it's a bit late happy birthday
from green so i hope he enjoys that
and i really hope that doesn't come
back to haunt me because
these things usually do
so i'm afraid that is all we have time
for today man we got a lot of stuff done
we did some more mining and we have we
got pranked and now we're in the end
game of the game thing with the turf
wall thing and stuff
man it is getting insane and hopefully
we can steal a win and get scar to help
us with the mansion because it looks
great but it's missing a little bit of
soul and i think scar can definitely
help that it's missing more than just a
little bit of soul if you ask me
feels like it's missing a whole lot back
here
but anyway i would say massive thank you
for watching the video and
please please please take a look in the
link down below if you are interested in
my merchandise show the barge design
some love or the pesky bird i hope you
enjoyed this video and i shall see you
in the next one good bye